MARIANNE GAA

mariannegaa@gmail.com (438) 777-4887 Toronto, Ontario Website | LinkedIn | GitHub

PROFILE

A continual learner with an analytical mind and an aptitude for detail-oriented roles. Formal education in statistics, research and project design. Self-taught programmer through Udemy and Codecademy coursework, StackOverflow resources, and a lot of trial and error. Resilient to frustration and inspired by challenging problems. Looking to break into a **Data Analyst** role. Bilingual in English and French.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS Excel, VBA, HTML, CSS, SQL, Python Programming, Web Scraping, Automation, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Statistics, Data Visualization, Jupyter Notebooks, Tableau, Git, Github and Command Line.

EDUCATION

Graduate Certificate in International Development, Humber College, 2016 — 2017 Toronto

Project design and programme management in the non-profit sector. Emphasis on collaboration and effective communication. Graduated with honours.

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology, Brock University, 2010 — 2014 St. Catharines Emphasis on statistics and research design, critical thinking, cognition and perception. Set solid foundation for sound data collection and analysis.

CERTIFICATES

Excel from Beginner to Advanced, Udemy, 2020 Formatting, formulas, macros and VBA.

MySQL for Data Analytics and Business Intelligence, Udemy, 2020 Relational schemas, complex subqueries, functions and stored procedures.

<u>Automate the Boring Stuff with Python Programming</u>, Udemy, 2020 Basic syntax, functions, control flow, modules, web scraping and automation.

Kampai Garden, Hostess, 2018 — 2019 Montreal

EXPERIENCE

- Client-facing role in a fast-paced environment, ensured smooth operation while providing an enjoyable guest experience
- Coordinated a diverse team to reduce turnaround time between services to 15 minutes in order to maximize capacity and business
- Responsible for promptly addressing all guest requests and concerns and for responding to all message and voice channels, with a proven ability to multitask

West Africa Network for Peace Building, Reporting & Communications Assistant, 2017 — 2018 Ghana

- Relationship building within the community through strategic communications
- Designed communications for distribution in collaboration with the Plan International team, expanding reach of conflict prevention programs to Ghana's youth demographic

MARIANNE GAA 2 of 2

- Summarization of key insights of projects and activities for the National Director and partner organization, The Fund for Peace
- Contributed to the organization's Annual Report 2016 and provided regional updates on conflicts within Ghana's mining communities for the National Action Plan 2018

HRG Inc., Customer Service Representative, 2014 — 2016 Montreal

- Very technical and detail oriented role, exchanged airfare through back end software which required excellent problem solving in challenging situations
- Exceptional statistics related to call handing and efficiency
- Perfect personal track record for eliminating surcharges from airlines by heeding airfare exchange rules meticulously
- Managed large monetary transactions while always remaining professional and discreet

COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT

GlobalMedic, Rapid Response Team, 2017 Toronto

- Packed water purifiers and hygiene kits that reached over 100,000 Syrian refugee families in Jordan and Syria
- Worked as part of a team to ensure that culturally appropriate items and supplies were included in the kits, before being sent out for distribution
- Attended annual training day in preparation to deploy in event of natural disaster or humanitarian crisis

Sustainable Development Goals Training, Volunteer Coordinator, 2017 Toronto

- Coordinated all volunteer aspects for the event at the community level
- Initiated communications and maintained contacts with local administrations and stakeholders
- Collaborated with communications and reporting specialist for media coverage of activities

International Development Institute, Marketing Coordinator, 2016 Toronto

- Responsible for the outreach and engagement of Humber College students for International Development Week 2017
- Designed and implemented comprehensive marketing strategies, heavily utilizing social media promotion to expand reach